What... what did you say?
你 你說什麼
I mean
我是說
that I didn't intend
我今天的本意
to humiliate Han Shuo today.
並不是想要欺辱韓爍的
You compared him with a musician at the Music and Dance Academy.
將他與教坊司樂人做比較
You don't think that's humiliation?
還不算欺辱嗎
I'm sorry.
對不起嘛
You're... sorry?
對 對不起
I know.
我知道
I made a mistake.
是我錯了
You... You are really apologizing?
你 你居然會道歉
I understand how Han Shuo feels.
韓爍的感受我明白
You had a sleep
睡了一覺起來
and found that everything had changed.
發現一切都變了
You looked around
茫然四顧
and there wasn't a single person you know.
周圍一個認識的人都沒有
You have to exhaust yourself
每天疲於奔命地
handling people around you every day.
跟周圍的人打交道
You can't have a proper meal
一頓飯也吃不好
and you're afraid other people will harm you.
提心吊膽地還怕別人害我
You also fear that you'll mess it up
還怕一個不小心搞砸了
and then you can't go home.
別說回家了
Perhaps you'll even be beheaded
搞不好還會身首異處
or shot to death.
萬箭穿心
I've got it.
我知道了
I'll go and apologize to Han Shuo now.
我現在就去給韓爍道歉
Pei Heng,
裴恆
I know you hated me before.
我知道你以前討厭我
But I'm different now.
但是現在的我跟以前不一樣了
Don't be disappointed in me, will you?
你別對我失望 好嗎
Okay.
好
Mr. Pei,
公子
you said you'd break off your engagement
你一說退婚
and Her Highness was so nervous and sad.
三公主就這麼緊張難過
It's really new to me.
也是新鮮
When has she ever
這麼多年
yielded over the years?
有誰見過三公主服過軟啊
She's willing
她居然為了您
to apologize to Young Master Han for you.
願意向韓少君賠禮道歉
It seems
看來
she cares very much about you.
她還是把您放心上的
Don't request Her Majesty
您就別奏請城主
to cancel your engagement.
取消婚約了
Ready.
準備
To its full extent.
滿弓準備
Come on, Xiaoqian.
小千加油
Han Shuo is not the same as another one.
此韓爍非彼韓爍
I can get along with him.
我還是可以跟他好好相處的
You can do it.
你可以的
Wait.
收箭
What is it you came for at this late hour?
三公主深夜來訪 所為何事
Do you think
難道是覺得
you haven't humiliated me enough?
白天教坊司的事還不夠嗎
Han Shuo.
韓爍
Young Master Han,
韓少君
I did the wrong thing today.
今天的確是我不對
I was reckless and inconsiderate.
是我行事魯莽 考慮不周了
You're a forgiving person.
你大人有大量
Don't take it to heart.
別往心裡去
Are you apologizing?
道歉啊
Do you think I'll believe you?
你覺得我會信嗎
If you don't believe me,
那你要是不信的話
there's only one thing I can do.
我只有一個辦法了
You were almost stripped in public today.
你今天險些被當眾扒了衣服
I'll make amends to you.
我賠給你
You...
你
Even if people in Huayuan City always do what they want,
花垣城就算是民風彪悍
few are as brazen as you.
也很少有你這樣厚顏無恥的吧
After I did this,
我這樣
we're even, aren't we?
咱倆算扯平了吧
How...
這
how can they be the same?
這怎麼能一樣呢
Oh, yes.
也對
You were also watched by a crowd today.
你今天還被當眾圍觀
Okay,
好
I'll go and walk around the street.
那我去大街上走一圈
Stop.
站住
Ready.
準備
Nominally you're my wife.
你好歹也是我名譽上的妻子
You can't dress like this in the street.
穿成這樣上街去
Don't look at me.
看我幹什麼
What do you think I should do, then?
那你說怎麼辦
I...
我
I'll take one more piece of clothes off?
我 再脫一件
What are you doing?
你幹什麼
Does Young Master Han want to do it himself?
難道少君要親自動手
You rascal!
流氓
-I... -You rascal.
我 你流氓
I didn't do anything.
我什麼都沒幹我
What were you yelling for?
你亂喊什麼
You yourself is the rascal.
簡直賊喊捉賊
What shall we do?
怎麼辦
You crazy woman,
你這個女人啊
you picked me up
第一次在街上見面
when we first met in the street.
就對我勾勾搭搭的
You wanted to see beauties
自己貪好美色
and took me to a brothel.
還帶著我一起逛青樓
When you saw Pei Heng, you were giddy with happiness
見了裴恆又難以自持
and got entangled with him.
跟他有扯不清的瓜葛
The baby you're carrying
你腹中這孽種
is his, isn't it?
保不齊就是他的吧
You've violated the Seven Regulations
你屢犯七出之罪
and ethics for women. You're dissipated
荒唐無度 不守婦道
by nature and... and... and...
生性放 放 放
How come you still have your gecko cinnabar?
你怎麼還有守宮砂呢
So you're a complicated man, aren't you?
這還有兩副面孔呢
Cold, unfeeling, shy and bewildered
冷酷無情 嬌羞無措
can all be used to describe you, right?
都讓你一個人演了 是吧
I have my gecko cinnabar.
守宮砂怎麼了
What's wrong with that?
有什麼問題嗎
Don't be fussy.
大驚小怪
But...
不
You... you are not pregnant?
你 你沒有身孕啊
I had to tell mother I was pregnant
這不是得騙母親說我有身孕
to save you.
才能救你出來嗎
You disregarded your honor
你為了救我
to save me?
竟然不顧自己的名節
Compared with someone's life,
名節跟人命
my honor is not important.
當然是人命重要
I really wanted to save you.
我是真心想救你的
Besides,
再說了
how much is my honor worth?
我這名節 能值幾個錢
That's right.
也是
If the rumors are true,
三公主若如同傳聞中的一樣
you can certainly
這名聲
discard your reputation.
不要也罷
Han Shuo,
韓少君
let's make an agreement.
從此以後我們約法三章
In public,
人前
we'll obey rules of Huayuan City
按照我們花垣城的規矩來
and you'll listen to me.
你聽我的
In private,
人後
we'll obey rules of Xuanhu City
按照你玄虎城的規矩來
and I'll listen to you.
我聽你的
You show me some respect
你敬我一尺
and I'll show you more.
我敬你一丈
This is our way to be
這也算是咱們名義上
a nominal couple.
夫妻的相處之道
That's settled.
就這麼說定了
Don't go back on it.
不許反悔
Stop.
站住
What now?
又怎麼了
Put on your clothes first.
把衣服穿上再出去
It's no big deal.
這算什麼
She's outside. What do we do?
出來了 怎麼辦
Ready. To its full extent.
準備 滿弓準備
Oh, no.
不好
It's late and cold.
夜深了 涼
Okay.
好
Thank you.
多謝少君好意
Zi Zhu!
梓竹
Your Highness, I've done my best.
二郡主 我盡力了
Chuchu,
楚楚
I've waited for this day
自我踏入花垣城那一刻起
since the moment I entered Huayuan City.
我就一直在等這一天
You and I were destined to fight.
你我之間固有一戰
Accept defeat.
認輸吧
Han Shuo,
韓爍
I had never suspected you,
我從未懷疑過你
yet you treated me so cruelly.
但你卻如此狠心
Today is the Double Seventh Festival.
今日是七夕
You injured my mother seriously
你竟在我母親遊街之際
when she was strolling in the street,
將她炸成重傷
lit the beacon
點燃狼煙
and attacked our city.
舉兵攻城
And Lin Qi.
還有林七
How many people around me have you killed?
我身邊到底還有多少人命喪你手
That's not all.
不止如此
I've also killed your sister, Chen Qianqian who you always love,
你從小疼到大的妹妹陳芊芊
with a cup of poisoned wine
也是大婚之夜
on the wedding night.
被我一杯毒酒送上西天
Qianqian was also killed by you?
芊芊也是你殺的
Han Shuo is really ruthless.
韓爍可真是心狠手辣呀
Though I've survived
雖然我現在躲過了
from his poisoned wine and arrows,
韓爍的毒酒 暗箭
I have to hang on till the ending
但我要堅持到大結局
so that I can go home.
才能回家
I can't die.
我不能死
I mustn't die.
我可千萬不能死
Do you get me?
都聽明白了嗎
Now I don't want to know
我現在根本就不想知道
how the apple and the banana can be together.
蘋果跟香蕉怎麼才能在一起
I just want to know
我就想知道
how the orange can save herself
它香蕉非要殺這橙子
when the banana is bent on killing her.
橙子怎麼才能保住性命
You're all outstanding members
三位先生都是說書行業的
of the storytellers.
業界翹楚
Help me think of a way
你們幫我想想
to make up the story
這故事要怎麼編才能
so that the orange will be saved.
才能保住這橙子
Does the orange have a bad reputation?
這橙子名聲很差嗎
She has done many evil deeds
劣跡斑斑
and she's notorious.
臭名遠揚
Did the orange offend the banana?
那橙子 得罪香蕉了嗎
She first took him for marriage,
開局搶親
then put him in prison
繼而害他入獄
and humiliated him in public.
隨後又當眾羞辱
The banana is merciless and vengeful.
香蕉心狠手辣 睚眥必報
He's a deep man
城府極深
and never hesitates to kill.
而且殺伐果決
Now he's licking his wounds
他現在就是在臥薪嚐膽
and waiting for a window of opportunity.
等待良機
When he recovers
待到後期
and builds up his strength,
等他病好了 解了困
he... he'll be like a tiger dashing down the mountain
他 他就是猛虎下深山
and a king fighting a war.
一身的王者正氣
He'll simply
可以說是
do everything he wants.
翻手為雲 覆手為雨
No one can stop him except the apple.
除了這蘋果 誰都擋不住
In that case,
那既然如此
why don't you just...
公主何不趁他危難之際
You can't write anything without killing someone, can you?
你不殺人寫不了戲啊
The banana will live.
香蕉得留著
He'll be useful in the future.
後來有用呢
Change his mind with love, then.
那就用愛來感動他
Talk some sense into him
曉之以情 動之以理
so that he'll repent and find a way out.
放下屠刀 回頭是岸
I don't know how to do that.
這我哪會呀
You need some events to change
洗白一個人物
people's opinion of a character, don't you?
也得有劇情基礎吧
The lines alone aren't enough.
光靠臺詞怎麼夠啊
There's nothing I can suggest, then.
那沒轍了
The orange's death
這除去橙子
is inevitable and everyone expects it.
那是眾望所歸 大勢所趨呀
Yes.
對呀
Your Highness,
三公主
why are you so bent on saving the orange?
你為何對橙子如此執念呢
Because Party A demands it.
甲方要求的
She invests in the drama
帶資進組了
and wants to live a few more days, okay?
想多演兩天行不行
What... what's Party A?
何 何為甲方啊
Me.
我
I'm Party A.
我就是甲方
I order you
我命令你們
to think of a way
趕緊給我想任何辦法
to save this orange now.
保住這顆橙子
Understood?
明白了嗎
Party A is quite willful.
甲方還挺任性的
She's rich.
有錢啊
Your Highness,
公主
the orange
這橙子
has to have some advantage, hasn't she?
總得有點過人之處吧
She's rich,
有錢
powerful
權勢滔天
and maybe a little pretty.
可能還有點好看
Those intrinsic ones.
內在的
Smart, resourceful and quick-witted.
機智 聰明 反應快
What about her skills?
技能類型的
She knows what will happen. Does it count?
未卜先知這算嗎
The orange knows the whole story
這橙子對整個故事的脈絡
like the back of her hand.
瞭如指掌
She knows how the banana will kill her,
這香蕉是如何殺了這橙子
lure the apple,
香蕉是如何勾搭上蘋果
scheme and order his men
香蕉是如何在暗中運籌帷幄
to stir up trouble in secret
興風作浪
and get the thing to continue to live
他是如何從蘋果那裡
from the apple.
得到良藥續命
She knows all these things.
橙子都知道啊
Your Highness,
三公主
why didn't you say that earlier?
這話你怎麼不早點說呢
Think about it.
你想想啊
Now that the orange is good at divination,
這橙子既然會占卜 擅推算
she definitely knows
那她一定知道
how she can avoid danger
怎麼樣可以趨利避害
and change it into her advantage.
逢凶化吉呀
Be more specific.
具體點
Use anything that betrays the banana,
利用香蕉的破綻
save him, help him, protect him,
救他 幫他 保護他
earn his trust,
獲得他的信任
change his impression of you
扭轉他的印象
and lower his guard.
降低他的戒心哪
Won't I be currying favor with him?
這不就是抱大腿嗎
You have to do that when you should.
那你該抱還得抱吧
Right.
對呀
How about this,
三位先生
gentlemen?
你們看這樣行不行
Suppose
假設
when the banana is seeing a spy,
這香蕉密會密探之時
the apple comes to encircle them
蘋果突然來圍剿
and the orange turns up in front
橙子挺身而出
of the banana and rescues him,
救香蕉於水火之中
do you think
你們說
the orange
這橙子
can earn the banana's trust?
她能獲得香蕉的信任嗎
Guys,
二位兄弟
was there such a story before?
這故事情節以前有嗎
There was
我讓它有
if I want it.
它就能有
Young Master.
少君
Our spy has got the defense map of Huayuan City
密探拿到了花垣城的城防圖
and wants to meet us at half past eleven
約我們子時二刻
on the moat tonight.
在護城河相見
Defense map?
城防圖
Your Highness, I've received a tip-off.
郡主 屬下收到密報
Someone will meet a spy of Xuanhu City
今夜子時二刻 護城河
at half past eleven tonight on the moat.
有人私通玄虎城密探
Who sent it?
誰送來的消息
I have no idea.
屬下 不知
Your Highness, Her Majesty is wary of Xuanhu City.
郡主 城主對玄虎城多有忌憚
If you can catch its spy,
若您能抓到玄虎城密探的把柄
she'll definitely regard you with favor.
一定能獲得城主的青睞
As for the tip-off,
至於密信
it's better
咱們寧可信其有
to believe it.
不可信其無
Qianqian has just married Han Shuo.
芊芊剛與韓爍成婚
If the spy of Xuanhu City is exposed now...
若此時玄虎密探暴露
You can't always think of the Third Princess.
您不能處處都為三公主著想啊
Your Highness, Her Majesty let you take charge
郡主 城主未經擢考
of the army without thinking about it.
就將司軍一職交給您
She has great expectations of you.
是對您寄予厚望
He's here. He's here.
來了 來了
The fish has bitten.
上鉤了
Listen,
我跟你說
we'll do it
一會兒就等楚楚帶人
when Chuchu is going
去捉韓爍的時候
to catch Han Shuo.
咱倆就衝上去
I'll say
就說
I'm the person who's meeting Han Shuo here
就說是我在這兒約的韓爍
and there isn't a spy of Xuanhu City.
沒有什麼玄虎城密探
And then
這樣一來
I'll get Han Shuo out of trouble
我幫韓爍解了圍
and he'll think I'm on his side.
他自然就把我當自己人了
What a brilliant idea.
這大腿 抱得真是漂亮
You're framing Young Master Han again.
你又這樣栽贓韓少君
If Her Majesty knows, she'll punish you.
被城主知道 她肯定責罰你
My mother is fond of me.
母后她寵愛我
She won't do that.
不會責罰我的
Han Shuo is sick.
主要就是這韓爍
He suffers from paranoia.
他有疑心病
I've got to cure him.
我得給他治治病
The time has come. Let's go.
時機到 行動
Why is no one here?
怎麼沒有人
Did they know we'd come?
難道走漏了風聲
Your Highness, someone's here.
二郡主 有人來了
On alert.
戒備
I'm here!
我來了
Qianqian, why is it you?
芊芊 怎麼是你啊
Ouch, ouch, ouch.
疼疼疼
You're going to meet someone here?
你在此處約了與人見面
Yes.
對啊
Where's he?
那約的人呢
He...
人
he didn't... he didn't come.
人 人沒 人沒來
Where's Han Shuo?
韓爍人呢
Did you arrange to meet him?
這約了嗎
Your Highness,
三公主
think it over before you tell us
您約了什麼人在此等候
who you're going to meet here.
可想好了再說
I'm going to meet...
我約了
No.
不是
Chuchu, did you get something wrong?
二姐 你是不是誤會什麼了
So you are the person who's going
原來約了玄虎城密探的人
to meet a spy of Xuanhu City.
是三公主
Colluding with the enemy is a capital offense.
這可是私通敵城的死罪
Collude with the enemy? Me?
私通敵城 我
Is that possible?
可能嗎
Don't talk nonsense.
你別瞎說
Han Shuo wasn't tricked but tricked me instead.
我被韓爍反套路了
This is an important matter
茲事體大
and I can't decide.
我做不了主
But I'll intercede with mother for you.
不過我會替你在母親面前求情的
Yes. Her Majesty loves you.
是啊 城主疼愛三公主
Even if you collude with the enemy,
即便是私通敵城
you'll be demoted to a commoner at worst.
最多不過廢為庶人
Oh, come to think of it,
不對 我想起來了
I came because I received a tip-off
是有人給我發密報
and it said someone was going
說有人在這兒
to meet a spy of Xuanhu City here.
約了玄虎城密探見面
I came to catch them.
我是來抓人的
With Zi Rui?
帶著梓銳
You are really eloquent,
三公主全憑一張嘴
Your Highness.
說什麼就是什麼
You said I colluded with the enemy.
那你說我私通敵城
Do you have any evidence?
那 人證物證何在
Chuchu, let me tell you the truth.
二姐 我實話跟你說吧
Actually I'm here to admire the moon.
其實我就是來看月亮的
Tonight
我這今晚
the moon is full, so I came.
剛好看月亮圓我就來了
And I happened to meet you here.
我這巧 又碰上你了
I'm sleepy.
這剛好 我也乏了
Zi Rui, let's go back.
來 梓銳 我們回去
Yes.
得嘞
Your Highness,
郡主
you just let her go?
您就這麼放三公主走
Her Majesty dotes on her and neglects you.
城主平時偏寵她 忽視您
It was such a good chance.
這 多好的機會呀
Qianqian seems to be
芊芊平時看起來
afraid of nothing
天不怕 地不怕
but actually she's the most cowardly.
實際上膽子最小
She doesn't dare to collude with the enemy.
通敵這種事情 她不敢做
I guess
我猜
if there's really such a spy of Xuanhu City,
若真有玄虎密探一事
it must be related to Han Shuo.
定與韓爍有關
Perhaps
也許
Qianqian was used by him.
芊芊是被他利用了
I'll have something on Han Shuo sooner or later.
我早晚要抓到韓爍的把柄
This way.
這邊
Quick.
走
This is suspicious.
此事有詐
What shall we do?
那怎麼辦
We'll make use of this trap
將計就計
and find the person behind it.
揪出背後指使之人
I told you he suffered from paranoia.
我就說他有疑心病吧
It's okay.
沒事
Watch how I turn the tables.
看我怎麼把劇情翻過來
Have you heard of this, Han Shuo?
敢問少君可曾聽過這樣一句話
Without faith, a man can't establish himself,
人無信不立
a business can't prosper
業無信不興
and a country will wane.
國無信則衰
Shouldn't we keep faith with other people?
咱們做人是不是得應該有點信義
You were invited to go there.
這明明是你受到了邀請
Why did you incriminate other people?
為何要栽贓他人呢
Are you talking about the moat?
三公主說的可是護城河一事
You could just ignore it
要麼 你就別去
but you went there and tricked me
去了你還故意繞一圈
into going on the boat. I was almost wronged.
引我上船 險些背鍋
It isn't right.
太不地道
You're quite honest.
三公主倒是坦誠
Let me ask you.
那麼敢問
I was almost tricked tonight.
韓某今晚差點遭人算計
Was it your doing?
此事是否是三公主所為
I tricked you?
我算計你
Do you know how much I worried about you?
你都不知道我有多擔心你啊
I heard
我聽人說
Chuchu was going to catch a spy of Xuanhu City
二姐今晚要去抓玄虎城密探
and I specially went to help you out.
我特意趕過去想要替你解圍
I had no idea you'd put me in that situation.
誰知被你反擺一道
How could you be so sure
三公主怎麼就能確定
I was the person the Second Princess was going to catch?
二郡主要抓的人就是韓某
How come I was sure?
我哪裡是確定
I was afraid.
我是生怕
I should go there
這萬一要是韓少君
in case it was you, shouldn't I?
我去了 有備無患對不對
That's to say,
這麼說來
you weren't trying to frame me
三公主沒有想要陷害韓某
but to save me?
反而是去救韓某的
Han Shuo,
韓少君啊
I've really taken pains to help you.
你可真是辜負了我一片苦心
Is that so?
當真如此
Don't move.
別動
You're hurt.
你受傷了
Yes,
對呀
I am hurt.
受傷了
I am hurt in order to save you.
為了救你受的傷
Why on earth did you try to save me?
三公主到底為何如此
Because I'm on your side.
因為我把你當自己人
Can you be
韓少君能不能
on my side, too?
把我也當自己人
Tell me if you have any problems.
有什麼難處你儘管提出來
I will go all out
我一定竭盡全力
to solve them for you
去幫韓少君排憂解難
and be of service to you.
任你差遣
Why are you willing to do so many things for me?
三公主為何對韓某如此掏心掏肺
Because...
因為
because I want you to be happy.
因為我想讓你開心
You want me
讓我
to be happy?
開心
It's useless talking so much.
多說無用
I'll prove it with my actions
反正我會用實際行動證明
that I'm good and I'm not clingy.
我便宜好用不黏人
You'll be satisfied.
包你滿意
It'll be a shame if I die.
死了可就太可惜了
Well,
那個
it's a good thing you didn't go there.
你今天幸好是沒去
Chuchu was so horrible.
二姐今天太嚇人了
I've got to have a late-night snack
我得回去趕緊吃點宵夜
and ginseng soup to steady my nerves.
喝點蔘湯壓壓驚
Have a good rest.
你早點休息啊
Young Master,
少君
do you think we can believe the Third Princess?
你說三公主的話能信嗎
Yes.
能信
But how come I always feel
可我怎麼總是覺著
it was her trickery?
這是三公主下的套
Think about this.
您看啊
She's always moody,
她平時就陰晴不定
unpredictable and dishonest.
喜怒無常 鬼話連篇
That's because she's an innocent girl.
那是她心思單純
This matter is related to the defense map
此事涉及城防圖
and a sealing wax bamboo tube that we use to communicate.
和我們平時通信用的火漆竹筒
The person who could get these two things
能拿到這兩樣東西的人
would never be Chen Qianqian, an idiot.
怎麼可能是陳芊芊這個草包
The Second Princess, Chen Chuchu,
倒是二郡主陳楚楚
is a prudent person.
心思縝密
It was most likely her doing.
此事多半是她所為
The Second Princess harmed us
二郡主害我們
because the two cities detest each other
是因為兩城交惡
and she wanted to distinguish herself.
她想趁此機會立功
But why did the Third Princess save us?
可三公主為何救我們呢
Does she want something in return?
難道她另有所圖
That should be true.
應該是了
Does she know our city is powerful
難道她知道咱們玄虎城實力強勁
and we can take Huayuan City any time?
隨時可以攻佔花垣城
Does she know our city is populous
難道她知道咱們玄虎城子民富庶
and awash with money?
存銀充裕
She doesn't want our forces
那她一不圖兵力
or money.
二不圖錢財
What does she want?
那她圖什麼呀
Me.
圖我
This woman
此女子
adores me.
鍾情我
She fell in love with you?
墜入情網了
That day her horse was panicked.
那日她馬匹受驚
I lent her a hand
是我挺身而出
and she was attracted to me
她便對我情根深種
and took me for marriage.
當街搶親
But she put you in prison on your wedding night.
大婚當夜她就害您入獄
She was trying to save me.
那是她為了救我才不顧名節
She even professed that she was pregnant.
謊稱有孕也要救我們
She also humiliated you in public.
她還在教坊司當眾羞辱您呢
She regretted it right away
那她立馬後悔了
and apologized to me. She even...
她向我道歉 她還
made amends to me.
小意溫柔
Young Master,
少君
even if the Third Princess has feelings for you,
即便是三公主對您有意
she's useless.
可她就是一個草包
She has no abilities or morals
無才無德不說
and she's infamous.
名聲極差
Will she be of help to us?
對我們有什麼助力嗎
I can use her to get the Dragon Bone.
我可以利用她奪得龍骨
How about the Second Princess?
那二郡主呢
Weren't you going to use her?
您當初不是說利用二郡主嗎
You said she was the most excellent princess of Huayuan City
您說她是花垣城最優秀的郡主
and she'd hopefully be the City Owner.
有望繼承城主之位
Also, if you married her, you'd get the Dragon Bone
得到她就能得到龍骨
and the black stone mine,
得到烏石礦
right?
對吧
I was wrong.
我錯了嘛
Now the Third Princess,
現在看來
Chen Qianqian, should be the one
應該是三公主陳芊芊
who the owner of Huayuan City favors.
更得花垣城主寵愛
She's also kind of clever.
還有幾分小聰明
If I give advice behind her,
如果有我在後面推波助瀾
she can definitely do great things.
定能堪當大任
Young Master.
少君
You've seen it.
你也看到了
The Second Princess cold-shouldered me
二郡主對我橫眉冷對的
and even plotted against me.
還設計害我
The Third Princess, Chen Qianqian,
反倒是三公主陳芊芊
has protected me a hundred times.
對我百般維護
Why should we ignore Chen Qianqian
咱們何必捨近求遠
and take the trouble
放著好好的陳芊芊不用
to approach the Second Princess?
去找那二郡主呢
That's
此言
reasonable.
有理
Young Master,
少君
brilliant.
英明
So all along no one showed up
所以 從頭到尾都沒有人現身
and you didn't find anything, right?
你什麼都沒查到 是嗎
I'm incompetent.
女兒無能
Of course you are.
當然無能
You've alerted the enemy.
如今你打草驚蛇
Now it's even harder for us
想要再抓住對方的把柄
to have something on them.
那就難上加難
I was being negligent. I'm sorry.
是女兒失職 考慮不周
Does this matter
此事
really have nothing to do with Han Shuo?
真的跟韓爍沒有關係嗎
It indeed has nothing to do with him.
確與韓少君無關
I don't know
女兒也不知
who gave us the information.
提供線索的人是什麼來頭
You were
你呀
too eager for honors
就是立功心切
to lack the judgment.
才失了分寸
Xuanhu City married a patient
如今 玄虎城派了個病秧子
to Huayuan City.
入贅花垣
There must be a follow-up to it.
這事 肯定還有後續
Yes.
是
Don't be angry, mother.
還請母親息怒
She's so careless.
做事如此不當心
How can I let her
讓我如何放心
be the City Owner?
將這城主之位傳給她
Your Majesty,
城主
the Second Princess
這二郡主
has been doing well.
已經做得很不錯了
Give her more time and chances.
你再給她一些時間和機會
I believe the Second Princess
我相信二郡主
won't let you down.
定不會讓城主失望的
And Qianqian.
可恨芊芊
She's disobedient and capable of nothing.
頑劣成性 碌碌無能
I've really given up on her.
叫我對她沒有半點指望
The Second and the Third Princesses are on good terms
這二郡主和三公主感情頗深
and they're like real sisters.
如同親姐妹
When the Second Princess succeeds you,
來日 二郡主繼承大任
I believe
我相信
she will take care of the Third Princess
一定會照顧好三公主的
and let her be free and well off all her life.
讓她一生閒散富貴
I hope so.
但願如此吧
My youngest daughter is incompetent
小女兒是個草包
and the eldest one is always sick.
大女兒又是個病秧子
My successor
少城主一職
shall be Chuchu.
楚楚當得
Your Highness.
郡主
Tomorrow Qianqian will go back
明日三妹就要銷假
to clan school after her leave.
回宗學堂了
I hear Young Master Han will enter the school, too.
聽說 韓少君也會一起入學
Help me ask Minister Pei for leave.
你替我去跟裴司學告假吧
Don't, Your Highness.
別啊 郡主
You can't be absent from school
您也不能為了躲著三公主
to avoid the Third Princess.
不去宗學堂
In my opinion,
以小人看
you should see and talk to people
您也該多和人見見面 說說話
and relax a bit.
散散心
You'll get worse if you're always alone.
老這樣一個人待著 會悶壞的
How worse can it be?
再壞還能怎樣
My mother has forgotten about me
母親早就忘了還有我這個女兒
and my sisters never think of me
妹妹也從沒有把我這個廢人
as their elder sister.
當成姐姐
Perhaps
說不定
The Third Princess will be mature after she got married
三公主成了親 就懂事了
and stop causing you trouble.
不再找您的麻煩了
Can marriage change a person?
成親就能改變一個人嗎
Han Shuo has done a good job, then.
那韓爍可真是功勞不小
When you meet someone you fancy,
等郡主您遇到了合心意的人
you'll also be different.
也會不一樣的
I'm afraid I'll die before that.
我怕是沒那個命
Put my new will away.
將我新修改的遺書收好
Why am I losing hair?
怎麼脫髮了
Zi Nian, close the door. Quickly.
梓年 快將門關上
Don't let the wind in.
不要讓風吹進來
And fetch me the barley, black sesame seeds,
再將我準備的大麥 黑芝麻
black beans, Euryale seeds, lotus stamen
黑豆 芡實 蓮鬚 核桃
and walnuts that I prepared.
這些食材全都拿來
Yes, Your Highness.
是 郡主
What kind of fate I'm suffering?
我這是什麼勞碌命
I have to study and take exams even in my dream.
連做夢都要讀書考試
I gotta wake up quickly.
還是得趕緊想辦法醒過來
Luckily Han Shuo won't think about killing me now.
還好現在韓爍不會總想著殺我了
Does that mean
那我是不是
I can pair him off with Chuchu?
可以撮合一下他和楚楚了呢
What are you doing?
你幹嗎
I'm a little deaf.
我耳背
I need to sit closer.
聽不清 坐近點
Don't think I don't know.
你別以為我不知道
You just want to be close to Minister Pei.
你就是想靠近裴司學
You've married Han Shuo.
你都已經有韓爍了
Mind what you say and see.
就應該管好你的眼睛和你的嘴巴
You're married.
三公主是成了親的人
You'd better stay away from other men.
最好與外男少接觸
No, no, no.
不是不是不是
I just want to have a class.
我上課呢
Forget it. This stupid man can't see the light.
算了 這蠢直男不開竅
There's nothing I can do.
我也沒辦法
According to rules of Huayuan City,
花垣城有規定
in the future, the princesses
日後 各位郡主
will all need to take the Crown Princess Election
都要參與少城主擢考
which consists of a literacy test
經過文試 策論
and discourse on politics.
兩道考驗
The one who does best in it
擢考的魁首
will be invested as the Crown Princess
會經城主冊封
by Her Majesty.
立為少城主
Daughters of officials will hold different positions
其餘官家之女則依據成績
according to your performances.
各自受封不同官職
You're all assets to our city
大家都是棟樑之材
and have a heavy schedule.
課業繁重
Today we'll play a game.
今日 我們就暫且做個遊戲
I will come first in archery.
騎射我肯定拿第一
The game is not about the Five Arts.
遊戲不在五藝之內
The Six Arts
君子六藝
are rites, music, archery, chariot racing, calligraphy and mathematics.
禮 樂 射 御 書 數
What are the Five Arts?
何為五藝
Performing music
撫琴奏樂
is just a method of pleasing women.
不過是取悅女人的伎倆
How can it be bracketed with the others?
豈能與其他相提並論
We won't talk about classics or history today.
今日 我們不學經 不論史
We'll compose verses.
對詩
The titles are "Wind", "Flowers", "Snow" and "Moon".
我以風花雪月為題
Choose one of them
每個人挑選一個字
and say two lines.
對兩句詩
They don't have to be of seven or five characters,
不論七言五言
or form a metrical poem or a quatrain.
不論律詩絕句
What matters is the rhyme.
重在合轍押韻
Let's start
我們就從
from the Second Princess.
二郡主開始吧
I'll choose wind.
我選風吧
Wind.
風
The water is blown and rippled.
吹水撩波有紋
Trees on the mountains are steady.
翻山越嶺無痕
Your Highness, you've mastered it
二郡主胸中有丘壑
and you can think big.
格局開闊
Princess Royal, it's your turn.
大郡主 到您了
Flowers.
花
Can not be red forever.
從無百日紅
Always vanish like a flash.
轉瞬即成空
Princess Royal,
大郡主
you win some and you lose some.
凡事有失必有得
Don't be too pessimistic.
不必太過悲觀
Miss Lin Qi, please.
林七小姐 請
Snow.
雪
I don't know what to say about snow.
雪我不會
Chen Qianqian,
陳芊芊
what are you laughing for?
你笑什麼
Can you do it?
難不成你會
I'm no better than you.
咱倆文化水平差不多
Of course I can't do it either.
你不會 我自然也不會
Why did you laugh, then?
那你還笑
I hear the Third Princess
聽聞三公主
has made progress recently.
近日有所進益
Why don't you give it a try?
不訪試一試
Minister Pei,
裴司學
don't stump her.
你就別為難三公主了
Everyone knows
誰不知道
she can read few words.
她斗大的字也不識幾個
How about this?
不如這樣
We'll take a bet.
咱們賭點什麼
If you can do it,
要是三公主能押得上韻
I'll
那我
clean the toilet.
就去掃茅廁
If you can't,
要是公主對不上來
you will clean the toilet.
那茅廁就歸三公主了
Are you so sure
你就這麼篤定我
that I can't do it?
一定對不上來
Just say if you dare or not.
你就說敢不敢
I dare not.
不敢
I'm too lazy.
我懶
I bet the Third Princess will win.
我押三公主贏
If you lose,
如果三公主輸了
I'll clean the toilet for you.
韓某替您掃茅廁
Must you do this?
至不至於啊
You involved yourself
為了看我出醜
to see me lose face.
自己都搭進去了
It's just composing a verse.
不就是對詩嗎
I wrote all your lines.
所有人的詞都是我寫的
It's a piece of cake for me.
幾句詩還不簡單
But Chen Qianqian is an illiterate person
還得穩住陳芊芊文盲的人設
who can't compose verses.
還要對詩
That's hard.
這簡直就是困難模式
If Han Shuo cleans the toilet for me,
不過要讓韓爍替我掃廁所
that will be hell.
那就變成地獄模式了
Why? Are you afraid?
怎麼 怕了
That's nonsense.
怕倒是沒有
I got it.
我想好了
Wind.
風
Ham,
火腿
salted fish,
鹹魚
sausage.
臘腸
Suckling pigs,
乳豬
baked pancakes,
烤饢
whole lamb.
全羊
Good.
通
Why is it good?
這哪兒通了
Ham, salted fish and sausage
火腿 鹹魚 香腸
are all air-dried.
都是風乾製成的
Roast suckling pigs, baked pancakes and roast whole lamb
而乳豬 烤饢 全羊
all need to be made with bellows.
全部都要用到風箱
I...
這
I'll have to clean the toilet, then?
這我就要去掃茅廁
I don't accept it.
我不服
What?
服
Okay, I'll make you accept it today.
我三公主今天對到你服
Flowers.
花
Cakes, desserts, red ginger.
糕餅 果子 紅姜
Scented tea, good and mellow wine.
香茗 清醇 佳釀
Good.
通
Are they still about flowers?
這哪兒有花呀
Cakes, desserts and red ginger cakes
糕餅 果子 紅薑餅
are usually made in the shape of flowers.
一般都是做成花的形狀
I don't need to explain flower teas
而花茶 花露 花釀
and wines, do I?
就不用解釋了吧
There's food and drink.
三公主這一句有吃有喝
It's more interesting
比起風那句
than the former one about wind.
就沒那麼燥了
These verses are wretched.
不過是一些歪詩
Compose ones on
有本事
snow and the moon if you can.
你再把雪和月也對上
Snow.
雪
Blancmange, cold platter and cool cake
奶凍 冰盤 涼糕
can be made when it snows.
雪天可以做
Jujube paste, five nuts and egg yolks
棗泥 五仁 蛋黃
can be eaten when the moon is full.
月圓才能吃
Lin Qi,
林七
clean the toilet, please.
那就只有辛苦你去掃一下茅廁嘍
Thank you.
謝謝
Minister Pei.
裴司學
Looks like
看來
you've really made
三公主學業上
progress in your studies.
果然有所進益
What are you doing?
這
You're back, my lady.
小姐 您回來了
You...
您這
What's the smell?
這什麼味啊
What's so smelly?
這 怎麼這麼臭啊
It's too smelly.
這好臭啊
Get lost!
都給我滾
Who asked you to come over?
誰讓你們過來的
How dare you say that I'm smelly?
竟然敢嫌棄我
She's the daughter of Her Majesty.
她畢竟是城主的女兒
I just can't accept it.
我就是不服氣
Chuchu is better than her in every respect
楚楚哪兒都比她強
but Her Majesty always likes Chen Qianqian
城主總是寵著陳芊芊
and picks on Chuchu.
總是挑楚楚的刺
I know you and the Second Princess are good friends.
知道你與二郡主情誼深厚
the Crown Princess to the City Owner.
肯定是板上釘釘的事
She's not worthy.
難當大任
That's true.
也對
Chen Qianqian is lacking in virtue.
陳芊芊德行有虧
How can she be the City Owner?
如何繼承城主之位
Wait.
等等
Are these all given by Chen Qianqian?
這些 是陳芊芊賞你的
Yes.
是
Her things are not allowed to be here.
我教坊司容不下陳芊芊的東西
You always flirt with each other.
平日裡你與她眉來眼去
She embarrassed me today.
她今天讓我出醜
I'll vent my anger on her man!
我就要拿她的人出氣
My lady,
小姐
he's also your man.
這也是您的人
What if you beat him to death?
打壞了怎麼好啊
Lin Qi beat you?
林七打你了
I infuriated Miss Lin
是小人惹惱了小姐
and she ordered me
小姐命令小人
to return these things to you.
把這些賞賜還給三公主
Lin Qi has obviously sent you
這林七分明就是送你來
to piss me off.
跟我示威的
She's too unruly.
林七太囂張了
I displeased her
看我不順眼
and she took it all out on you.
把氣全部撒在你身上
She wasn't hitting you
這哪是打你
but me.
這分明就是在打我
Your Highness, don't mind it.
三公主 不必介懷
It didn't hurt when she whipped me.
這鞭子打在身上 不疼
But if
但是若
you're angered,
惹三公主動怒
my heart
我蘇沐
will ache.
會心疼的